A Guide to the Daisy Lester Avery Papers, 1906-1982
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Daisy Lester Avery Papers, 1906-1982
The Library of Virginia
50052
10.225 cubic feet (26 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased.
Biographical Information
Daisy Mae Lester was born on 13 September 1889. She was the daughter of Luther Calvin Lester and Nancy Elizabeth Davis. She married James Thomas Avery, Sr. (1886-1918) on 20 July 1910. They lived in New York City for a short time where he was employed by Norfolk Southern Railroad. He was transferred to Norfolk in 1918, and died there on 2 October 1918. Daisy Lester Avery moved to Richmond after her husband's death. She became involved in various social, civic, and religous groups, namely the United Confederate Veterans, and the United Daughters of the Confederacy. She joined the latter's Stonewall Jackson Chapter in 1922, and later served as its president from 1950 to 1954. Avery organized the annual "Massing of the Flags," held on June 3 at the Jefferson Davis Monument in Richmond to commemorate the birthday of the former Confederate president. She also organized the Centennial Chapter of the UDC in 1961, and two chapters of the Children of the Confederacy. She was also involved with the Council on Adult Education, the Richmond Public Forum, and Richmond League of Women Voters. Avery also studied art at the Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts in Philadelphia. She was a member of Hanover Avenue Christian Church. She had three children: Virginia Lucille Avery (1911-1955), James Thomas Avery, Jr. (1915-1981), and Marsden Perry Avery (1918-1920). Daisy Lester Avery died in Richmond on 9 March 1983, and is buried in Hollywood Cemetery.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1906-1982, of Daisy Lester Avery (1889-1983) of Richmond, Virginia, including correspondence and subject files, mainly relating to her involvement with the United Confederate Veterans and the United Daughters of the Confederacy. The collection also contains letters of her son, James Thomas Avery, Jr. (1915-1981), while he was attending the Virginia Military Institute.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
I. Correspondence.
II. Subject Files.
III. James Thomas Avery, Jr. Letters.
Contents List
- Series I. Correspondence, 1906-1982., Extent: 4 boxes. (Box 1-3)
  The earliest corrrespondence are primarily letters written by her husband James Thomas Avery, Sr. (1886-1918) while he was in New York on business. There are also congratulatory letters written to them following the birth of their son, James Thomas Avery, Jr. in 1915. Beginning in the 1930's, the letters deal with her activities with the United Confederate Veterans as adjutant general of the Virginia Division. Later correspondence is focused on her involvement with the United Daughters of the Confederacy, as well as other social and civic activities, and family news. There is a good deal of correspondence concerning Avery's efforts on legislation affecting the R. E. Lee Camp Confederate Soldiers' Home in Richmond, as well as letters relating to the "Massing of the Flags" celebration, that was held annually in Richmond on June 3rd to commemorate the birth of Jefferson Davis. Principal correspondents include her son and his wife, Hester Vail Avery (1915-1983), her daughter Virginia Avery Burnett (1911-1955), and her sister Lucille C. Mills (ca. 1883-1967), as well as numerous officers of the United Confederate Veterans and the United Daughters of the Confederacy.
  Chronological.
  - 1906. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1910. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1911. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1912. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1913. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1914. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1915. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1916. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1918. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1919. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1920. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1922. (Box 1, Folder 11a)
  - 1924. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1929. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1930. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1933. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1934. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1935. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 1936 (January-June). (Box 1a, Folder 1)
  - 1936 (July-December). (Box 1a, Folder 2)
  - 1937. (Box 1a, Folder 3)
  - 1938. (Box 1a, Folder 4)
  - 1940. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1942. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1944. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1945. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1947. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1948. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1949. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1950. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1951. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1952. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1953. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 1954. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 1955. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 1956. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 1957. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 1958. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 1959. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 1960. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 1961. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1962. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 1963. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 1964. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 1965. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 1966. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 1967. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 1968. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 1969. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 1970. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 1971. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 1972. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 1973. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 1974. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 1975. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 1976. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - 1977. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - 1978. (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - 1979. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - 1980. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - 1981. (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - 1982. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - n.d.. (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Series II. Subject Files, 1911-1982., Extent: 13 boxes. (Box 4-19)
  The subject files include address books and calendars, artwork, clippings, greeting cards, insurance papers, invitations, notes and notebooks, photographs, poetry and song lyrics, programs, publications, sketchbooks, and sympathy cards and letters. There is also information relating to Avery's involvement in various Confederate organizations contained in the subject files. There are records of the Children of the Confederacy, and the Stonewall Jackson Chapter and Centennial Chapter of the United Daughters of the Confederacy, including handbooks, membership applications, minutes, programs, reports, and yearbooks. There are files relating to Jefferson Davis, including biographical information, efforts to have him elected to the Hall of Fame for Great Americans, memorial addresses, publications, and planning materials concerning the annual June 3rd "Massing of the Flags" celebration in Richmond. The subject files also include Avery's work on legislation related to the R. E. Lee Camp Confederate Soldiers' Home, and a notebook containing a list of her work with Confederate groups from 1922 to 1965.
  Of particular note in the subject files are lists of "inmates," or residents, of the R. E. Lee Camp Confederate Soldiers' Home. These appear to be transcriptions of the registers included in LVA Accession 24736. There are two typescript lists, or "rolls," of former residents. The first covers surnames beginning with A-G, and includes the person's admission date, name, and regimental history. The second list is more detailed, and is 440 pages in length. It covers surnames A-Z, and includes admission date, name, age, where born, regimental history, cause of admission, by whom sent, cause of discharge (death date is often noted), and remarks. The two lists are arranged by first letter of the surname, and thereunder chronologically by date of admission. Some information contained in the lists has been lost due to water and mold damage to the originals. For preservation reasons, the entire two lists have been photocopied.
  - Account Book, 1953-1956. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Accounts and Receipts. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Adams Express Company - Claim, 1917. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Address Book, 1972. (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
  - Address Books. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Addresses - U.D.C.. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Aetna Life Insurance Company. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Air Force Academy Library Donation, 1959. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Aloha Study Group, 1917-1918. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Artwork. (Box 4, Folder 11-13)
  - Artwork (Oversize). (Box 19)
  - As Falls The Leaf by Berta King Ray. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Atlantic Life Insurance Company. (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Avery, Daisy L. - 80th Birthday, 1969. (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Avery, James T. - Military Certificates (Copies by DLA). (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Bank Book, 1918. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Bank of Commerce and Trusts, 1936. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Battle of Front Royal Centennial Commemoration, 1962. (Box 5, Folder 3a)
  - Bibliographic Catalogue of the Portraits in the Confederate Memorial Institute,1929. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Books on the War Between the States. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Business/Calling Cards. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Calendars, 1964, 1965, 1971. (Box 19)
  - Candy Sale. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Centennial Chapter. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Centennial Chapter - Membership Applications. (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
  - Centennial Chapter - Memorials. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Centennial Chapter - Minutes. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Centennial Chapter - Reports. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Chenette, Maude Howe. (Box 5, Folder 13a)
  - Children of the Confederacy. (Box 5, Folder 14-16)
  - Christian Woman's Board of Missions. (Box 5a, Folder 1)
  - Clarke, Florence Moore. (Box 5a, Folder 2)
  - Clay Ward Young Democrats, 1939. (Box 5a, Folder 3)
  - Clippings. (Box 5a, Folder 4)
  - Coat of Arms. (Box 5a, Folder 5)
  - Confederate Activities of Daisy Lester Avery, 1922-1965. (Box 5a, Folder 6)
  - Confederate Costume Ball - Muscicians' Contract, 1952. (Box 5a, Folder 7)
  - Confederate Costume Ball - Programs, 1951-1955. (Box 5a, Folder 8)
  - Confederate Hospital Marker, 1936. (Box 5a, Folder 9)
  - Confederate Pensions Paid, 1 January 1936. (Box 5a, Folder 10)
  - Confederate Veterans - Notecards. (Box 5a, Folder 11)
  - Connecticut General Life Insurance Company. (Box 5a, Folder 12)
  - Constitutions and By-Laws. (Box 5a, Folder 13)
  - Cross of Military Service. (Box 5a, Folder 14-15)
  - Diary, 13-22 September 1947. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Dickens Club, 1935. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Disability Benefits. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - EDO Corporation. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Education/Scholarships - U.D.C., 1964. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Employment Applications. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Ephemera. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Equitable Life Assurance Society. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Fidelity and Casualty Company of New York. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Financial Statement - James T. Avery, 1917. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Forty Years With the Virginia Division, United Daughters of the Confederacy by Mrs. Cabell Smith. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Funeral Book - Virginia A. Burnett. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Furnace Repair, 1917. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Garden Club Speech, 1937. (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - General Assembly, 1958. (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Greeting Cards - Birthday. (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Greeting Cards - Christmas. (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Greeting Cards - Easter. (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Greeting Cards - Get Well. (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
  - Guest Register, 1980-1981. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Handbooks - United Daughters of the Confederacy, 1959, 1972. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Hanover Avenue Christian Church. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - History of the Virginia Division, United Daughters of the Confederacy, 1895-1967. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Inaugural Program, 1942. (Box 7, Folder 6a)
  - Inmates of the R. E. Lee Camp Confederate Soldiers' Home (A-G). (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Inmates of the R. E. Lee Camp Confederate Soldiers' Home (A-Z). (Box 7, Folder 8-11)
  - Invitations. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - James B. Gordon Chapter, U.D.C. - History, 1973. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Jefferson Davis 150th Anniversary, 1958. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Jefferson Davis - Biographical Information. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Jefferson Davis - Election to Hall of Fame for Great Americans. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Jefferson Davis Highway Banquet Address. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Jefferson Davis Memorial Address (WRVA), 3 June 1937. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Jefferson Davis Memorial Chapel. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Jefferson Davis - Shrines in Richmond. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Lanier, Sidney - Election to Hall of Fame. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - League of Women Voters. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Leases. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - List of U.C.V. Camps in Virginia. (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - List of U.D.C. Conventions. (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - The Making of a President: Jefferson Davis, 1861 by Frank E. Vandiver. (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Manassas Chapter - History. (Box 8, Folder 15a)
  - Massing of the Flags, 1966. (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Massing of the Flags, 1967. (Box 8, Folder 17-21)
  - Massing of the Flags, 1968. (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Massing of the Flags, 1969. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Massing of the Flags, 1970. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Massing of the Flags, 1971. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Massing of the Flags, 1972. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Massing of the Flags, 1973. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Massing of the Flags, 1974. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Massing of the Flags, 1975. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Massing of the Flags, 1976. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Massing of the Flags, 1977. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Massing of the Flags, 1978. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Massing of the Flags, 1979. (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Massing of the Flags, 1980. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Massing of the Flags, 1981. (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Massing of the Flags, 1982. (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Medical College of Virginia Hospital. (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Medical-Surgical Plan of New Jersey. (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Membership Cards. (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Metropolitan Life Insurance Company. (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Minutes - U.D.C. 43rd Annual Convention, Dallas, TX, 18-21 November 1936. (Box 10)
  - Minutes - U.D.C. 44th Annual Convention, Richmond, VA, 9-12 November 1937. (Box 10)
  - Minutes - U.D.C. 52nd Annual Convention, Houston, TX, 21-23 November 1945. (Box 10)
  - Minutes - U.D.C. 56th Annual Convention, New Orleans, LA, 6-11 November 1949. (Box 10)
  - Minutes - U.D.C. 61st Annual Convention, Roanoke, VA, 7-11 November 1954. (Box 11)
  - Minutes - U.D.C. 73rd Annual Convention, Richmond, VA, 5-10 November 1966. (Box 11)
  - Minutes - U.D.C. 74th Annual Convention, Hot Springs, AR, 4-9 November 1967. (Box 11)
  - U.D.C. 75th Annual Convention, Richmond, VA - Notebooks (2) 9-14 November 1968. (Box 11)
  - Minutes - U.D.C. 86th Annual Convention, Daytona Beach, FL, 10-15 November 1979. (Box 11)
  - Minutes - U.D.C., Virginia Division, 40th Annual Convention, Roanoke, VA, 1-4 October 1935. (Box 11)
  - Minutes - U.D.C., Virginia Division, 46th Annual Convention, Bristol, VA, 7-10 October 1941. (Box 11)
  - Minutes - U.D.C., Virginia Division, 47th Annual Convention, Richmond, VA, 6-8 October 1942. (Box 11)
  - Minutes - U.D.C., Virginia Division, 48th Annual Convention, Roanoke, VA, 5-7 October 1943. (Box 11a)
  - Minutes - U.D.C., Virginia Division, Executive Board, Richmond, VA, 3-4 October 1944. (Box 11a)
  - Minutes - U.D.C., Virginia Division, 51st Annual Convention, Richmond, VA, 1-3 October 1946. (Box 11a)
  - Minutes - U.D.C., Virginia Division, 52nd Annual Convention, Roanoke, VA, 6-8 October 1947. (Box 11a)
  - Minutes - U.D.C., Virginia Division, 53rd Annual Convention, Petersburg, VA, 5-7 October 1948. (Box 11a)
  - Minutes - U.D.C., Virginia Division, 55th Annual Convention, Norfolk, VA, 3-5 October 1950. (Box 11a)
  - Minutes - U.D.C., Virginia Division, 56th Annual Convention, Natural Bridge, VA, 2-4 October 1951. (Box 11a)
  - Minutes - U.D.C., Virginia Division, 63rd Annual Convention, Natural Bridge, VA, 7-9 October 1958. (Box 11a)
  - Minutes - U.D.C., Virginia Division, 73rd Annual Convention, Front Royal, VA, 1-3 October 1968. (Box 11a)
  - Minutes - U.D.C., Virginia Division, 76th Annual Convention, Roanoke, VA, 5-7 October 1971. (Box 11a)
  - Minutes - U.D.C., Virginia Division, 86th Annual Convention, Winchester, VA, 6-8 October 1981. (Box 11a)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Monuments and Historic Markers Committee. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Navy Band - Confederate Costume Ball, 1951. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Northern Insurance Company of New York. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Northwestern Mutual Life Insurance Company. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Notebooks. (Box 13)
  - Notes. (Box 12, Folder 6-7)
  - Obituary - James Thomas Avery. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Ogden, Karma Deane. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Orange Storage Warehouse Company. (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Park Place No. 12 Property, 1911-1913. (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Pensions - General Assembly Appropriations, 1938. (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Perry, Marsden J.. (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Photographs. (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Poetry and Song Lyrics. (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Poetry Society of Virginia. (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Portrait Gallery and Library of R. E. Lee Camp, No. 1, Confederate Veterans,1913. (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Postcards. (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Programs. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - R. E. Lee Camp No. 1 - Deed to U.D.C. Virginia Division, 1935-1936. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - R. E. Lee Camp No. 1 - Opposition to Proposed Lease, 1949. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Real Estate Loan Deposit Company. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Richmond Light Infantry Blues - Permanent Memorial Committee. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Richmond Public Forum. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Richmond-Stonewall Jackson Chapter. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Richmond U.D.C. Chapters. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Rosters - Magruder Camp and Warwick Beauregards, Newport News. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - School Examination, 1925. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Scrapbook - Stonewall Jackson Chapter, 1937-1942. (Box 19)
  - Senate Bill 34 - VMFA Parking Lot, 1934. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Sherritt Flag Company. (Box 14, Folder 11a)
  - Simplified Training Course. (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Sketch of the Origin and Erection of the Confederate Memorial Institute. (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Sketchbooks. (Box 15-16)
  - Sons of Confederate Veterans - Lee-Jackson Camp. (Box 14, Folder 13a)
  - Stationary. (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Stonewall Jackson Chapter. (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Stonewall Jackson Chapter - Reports, 1953. (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Stonewall Jackson - Election to Hall of Fame. (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Stonewall Jackson - Man: And His Fellowman by America Ann Hunter, 1956. (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Story of the Jefferson Davis Funeral Train. (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Student Writers' Club. (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Swartwout and Appenzellar. (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Sympathy Cards and Letters - Death of James Thomas Avery, 1918-1919. (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Sympathy Cards and Letters - Death of Virginia A. Burnett, 1955. (Box 17, Folder 1-4)
  - Taxes. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Tickets. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Travelers Insurance Company. (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - U.D.C. Magazine, August-September 1971. (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - The U.D.C. of Richmond, Virginia by Daisy Lester Avery. (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - United Confederate Veterans - Reunion, 1937. (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - United Confederate Veterans, Virginia Division - Reunion, 1935. (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - United Confederate Veterans, Virginia Division - Reunion, 1936. (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - United Confederate Veterans, Virginia Division - Reunion, 1937. (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - United Daughters of the Confederacy - Programs. (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
  - United Daughters of the Confederacy, Virginia Division - Annual Convention, 1964. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - United Daughters of the Confederacy, Virginia Division - Minutes (Executive Board), 1967. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - United Daughters of the Confederacy, Virginia Division - Newsletter, May 1982. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - United Daughters of the Confederacy, Virginia Division - Programs 1964. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - United Daughters of the Confederacy, Virginia Division, Fifth District. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Federation of Women's Clubs. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - West-End Christian Church - Directory. (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Wev, Oscar C.B.. (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Will (Draft). (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Will of Daisy Lester Avery, 1918. (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Woodrow Wilson Memorial Scholarship - Card Party, 1925. (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Works Progress Administration Historical Inventory. (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Yearbooks - Centennial Chapter. (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Yearbooks - Children of the Confederacy. (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Yearbooks - Lee Chapter. (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Yearbooks - Mildred Lee Chapter. (Box 18, Folder 17a)
  - Yearbooks - Pickett-Buchanan Chapter. (Box 18, Folder 17b)
  - Yearbooks - Richmond-Stonewall Jackson Chapter. (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Yearbooks - Stonewall Jackson Chapter. (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Yearbooks - U.D.C., Virginia Division. (Box 18, Folder 20)
- Series III. James Thomas Avery, Jr. Letters, 1930-1934., Extent: 4 boxes. (Box 21-24)
  The series of letters of her son, James Thomas Avery, Jr., include correspondence written while he was attending Camp Dudley, a boys' camp in Westport-on-Lake Champlain, New York in 1930. Topics include his participation in camp activities, including swimming, baseball, basketball, tennis, rifle practice, attending movies, as well as his health, family news and weather. Most of this series, however, are letters written to him while he was attending the Virginia Military Institute from 1931 to 1934. Most of the letters are from his mother, sister, and aunt, but there are also many from friends. Topics include inquiries and comments about his classes, grades, fellow cadets, and extracurricular activities. The letters also contain family news, especially concerning automobile trips around the country, his mother's social and civic activities, school activities, and news of mutual acquaintances in Richmond. The later letters in this series were written to him while he was attending ROTC training at Camp Hoyle, Maryland.
  - 1930 (June). (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - 1930 (July 1-15). (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - 1930 (July 16-31). (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - 1930 (August). (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - 1931 (September 1-15). (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - 1931 (September 16-30). (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - 1931 (October 1-15). (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - 1931 (October 16-31). (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - 1931 (November). (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - 1931 (December). (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - 1932 (January 1-15). (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - 1932 (January 16-31). (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - 1932 (February). (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - 1932 (March). (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - 1932 (April). (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - 1932 (May). (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - 1932 (June-August). (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - 1932 (September). (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - 1932 (October). (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - 1932 (November). (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - 1932 (December). (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - 1933 (January). (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - 1933 (February). (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - 1933 (March). (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - 1933 (April). (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - 1933 (May). (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - 1933 (June). (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - 1933 (September). (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - 1933 (October). (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - 1933 (November). (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - 1933 (December). (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - 1934 (January). (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - 1934 (February). (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - 1934 (March). (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - 1934 (April). (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - 1934 (May 1-15). (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - 1934 (May 16-31). (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - 1934 (June). (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - 1934 (July). (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - 1934 (August). (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - n.d.. (Box 23, Folder 7)